I told you, no! I'm not for sale!
He is my beloved grandchild. Um, if you want a puppet, please take this wood-carved one.
Ah, what I want is that talking wooden puppet.
Please, sell it to me.
How many times do I have to tell you?! I'm not for sale! / 500 lire. How about 500 lire?
I'll give you 1,000 lire!
2,000 lire!
3,000 lire!
5,000 lire!
7,000 lire!
8,000 lire! No, 10,000 lire!
All right, I'll pay 15,000 lire!
That's more than you could earn in a lifetime!
He's not for sale! He is not for sale!
Back!
Stupid puppet seller!
That's why I said I didn't want to come to a town like this!
Hey, watch out!
You look like a puppet, yet you're so violent!
I'm not a puppet!
Ugh!
I want to be alone!
Go away!
Hurry up and get lost!
Humans really are nasty. Let's go!
Get out of here!
Mokku!
Grandpa, let's go back to the village.
This is part of your learning, too.
Come along now. I'll buy you something nice.
(coins clinking)
How's that, Mokku? From any angle, you look just like a fine human, don't you?
(laughter)
But if you spend this much money, won't we not be able to stay at an inn?
The sun is still high. The puppets will sell.
Thanks, Grandpa! I'm going out for a bit.
Hey, hey, hold on! Where are you going? You'll fall if you run like that!
Little girl! Girl from earlier! Aren't you here? Little girl!
Oh, that mean puppet is back.
We have to be careful.
Hey, sorry about earlier. I was just worked up.
Huh, you came to apologize? That's a surprise.
And also, I wanted you to see how I look now.
Do I look human?
Yeah, as long as you don't say anything, you definitely look human.
You don't look like a puppet at all.
Thanks! Hearing that from you gives me real confidence.
Can you talk to butterflies?
So pretty...
Hey, what's wrong?
N-N-No, uh, I was j-just talking to myself. S-Sorry.
Oh, you don't have to apologize.
Talking to butterflies...
That's simply impossible, isn't it?
Y-Yes, exactly. It's impossible.
I'm Mellerie. What's your name?
Oh, yes. I-I'm a pup... ugh... I'm Mokku the human.
My, "Mokku the human"?
(Mother's voice)
(Girl) Please, help me!
(Girl) Huh?
(Girl) She's a witch!
(Girl) Hurry!
(Girl) A witch!?
(Girl) All right!
(Girl) You mustn't go with him!
(Girl) Young mistress! Lady Mellerie!
How strange...
You're safe now.
Thank you, Mokku.
Yvonne is actually my tutor.
A tutor?
Oh, you don't know what a tutor is, Mokku?
It's someone who teaches you lessons at home.
Don't you have one?
My tutor is Grandpa.
He brought me along, saying it's important to see the world and learn.
Is he nice?
He's really kind.
Yvonne is very strict. She never lets me go outside alone.
Poor Mellerie.
Yes, terribly so.
All right, I'll beat up that awful person for you!
You're so sweet.
Not really...
Grandpa!
Ah, Mokku. Where on earth have you been?
This is my girlfriend, Mellerie.
I'm Mellerie Luca. Nice to meet you.
What? Then are you the daughter of that famous millionaire?
Yes, I am.
Whoa, your family is that rich?
Papa just owns lots of banks and shipping companies. That's all.
Hmm, I don't really like rich people.
Me neither. I envy you.
[[NO AUDIO]]
Come now, Mellerie, what is the matter?
It's boring always being with you, Yvonne.
To enter high society, you need proper discipline and refinement.
I don't care about high society!
I just want to run along the beach with Mokku,
walk through the town, and chase butterflies in the flower fields... Mellerie?
Goodness, what are you saying? In just one day, how did you become such a bad girl, Mellerie?
Now, Mama, wait.
This is the first time I've ever seen Mellerie look so serious, yet so bright and full of life.
But... please, Papa, it's all right for Mokku to come to our house, isn't it?
But, Mellerie, as for that... Um, even I can attend that high-and-mighty society thing if I just study properly!
(Children laughing)
(Laughter)
(Screaming)
That was close... That startled me.
Thank you, Mokku.
You're surprisingly a coward, Mokku. After saying you'd beat up Papa, Mama, and Yvonne! Well, I had no idea Mellerie's house would be so big and grand!
Oh, there's a starling's nest!
I'll get it for you.
Look!
Wait, Mokku!
Mokku, that's dangerous! Be careful!
It's all right, it's all right!
Is there anything inside?
There are eggs!
Show me, too!
All right!
Mokku!
You're not being honest.
Huh? What are you doing all the way out here?
You're hiding the fact that you're a wooden puppet from that girl.
I'm not hiding anything!
Then why don't you just tell her you're a wooden puppet?
Mind your own business!
You're hiding it because you fell for Mellerie.
You're a coward, Mokku.
Shut up!
Hey, wait, Mokku!
Mokku!
Mokku! Are you all right?
I'm totally fine!
Thank goodness. Are you really all right?
Your body is so hard, Mokku.
Huh?
That's because I've trained my body.
It felt as solid as an oak tree...
Thank you all for gathering here today for Mellerie's birthday.
Grandpa!
Ah, welcome.
Mokku, I invited him without telling you.
Grandfather, thank you for coming. Please, come in.
They insisted, you see.
This is delicious. Truly delicious.
Just chew it...
(Grandpa sobbing)
Grandpa, please just go home!
Huh?
I wish you had never come!
Mokku...
What is the matter, Mokku?
Grandpa has always been poor, so he doesn't belong with high-class people!
I understand. Grandpa will go home.
(Laughter)
Stop it, Mokku.
Mokku, you shouldn't.
It's fine. It's better than being made fun of.
Mellerie, let's dance.
Huh?
After dinner, of course. After all, I'm a gentleman.
[(NO AUDIO)]
Mokku? Will you stay here forever?
Yeah.
When I grow up, I want to be your wife.
Really?
Really. You can kiss me.
We can't. We're still just kids.
But we're going to get married when we grow up, right?
Well, yeah, but...
Wearing gloves and acting fancy... There's no way a wooden puppet can grow up, let alone get married.
Why don't you tell her the truth? Mokku, what's wrong?
It's nothing.
You can't keep hiding it forever. What are you going to do?
When I grow up, I'm going to be Mokku's bride.
But I'm a wooden puppet.
I can't marry Mellerie.
[[NO AUDIO]]
Ah, the Oak Tree Fairy!
Mokku, tell Mellerie the truth.
Otherwise, you will only make yourself miserable.
I did tell her! / You must never lie to someone you love.
I don't love her! I just kind of like her!
Because Grandfather bought you clothes, he had no money left for an inn and is working on a farm.
Yet you sleep in such a soft bed without a care in the world?
But Grandpa hates rich people, so he left on his own.
Mokku, how long are you going to keep lying?
All right! I won't lie anymore, so please turn my nose back to normal!
With such an embarrassing nose, he can't go see Mellerie.
If you do not have the courage to tell the truth, then it is not true love.
Do you understand, Mokku?
Mokku, what you must do is become a real human with a kind and righteous heart.
I understand. I'll tell the truth.
Goodbye, Mokku. Be brave.
Mokku, what's wrong?
Uh, it's nothing.
Really?
Mellerie!
I'm going to go check on Grandpa!
Mokku...
I can't! I can't say it! I just don't have the courage!
Help!
Help us!
Look, it went that way!
All right!
Wooden puppet, save us!
Oh, butterflies!
They'll turn us into specimens!
Quick, go!
All right!
You're safe now.
Hurry and get away!
Hey! What are you doing?!
Be careful!
Why, you...!
Ah!
Ow, ow, ow! That hurts!
What?
You damn little brat...!
You?
Of course! My body is made of oak!
Damn it! You monster! Get him, everyone!
Take this!
Take that!
How dare you insult Grandpa and me last night!
Mokku! Stop it!
[(NO AUDIO)]
Mokku... You're... Wait! I... I have to say it myself.
I'm a wooden puppet made from an oak tree.
Mellerie, this is who I really am.
Mellerie...
I'm not mature enough to love you yet.
I have to work hard to become a real human.
Thank you, Mellerie. Goodbye.
He'll come back to see you again.
Mokku...
Mokku!
(Grandfather's face)
Cheer up, Mokku. You've learned an important lesson that school could never teach you. Come on, let's go.
Yes.
Grandfather!
Mokku!
Now, wait! It's dangerous to run so fast!
One day, adults who came into the village plotted to make money, and...
They plan to build a huge amusement park in the forest, and chop down the Oak Tree where the Fairy who gave Mokku life lives.
To protect the Fairy and the peaceful lives of the crows and squirrels, Mokku takes a stand.
Can Mokku save the Oak Tree from the sharp axe about to fall? Find out next week on Kashi no Ki Mokku!